<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-03T20:37:47-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jieruei Chang</title><entry><title type="html">NASA Scientist For A Day Entry: Titan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/2019/02/14/titan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NASA Scientist For A Day Entry: Titan" /><published>2019-02-14T12:10:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-14T12:10:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/2019/02/14/titan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/2019/02/14/titan.html">&lt;p&gt;Of all the celestial objects in the solar system, there are only two known to have stable liquid on their surface. One is Earth. The other is Titan, the largest Saturnian moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remarkably similar to Earth, Titan is a moon with lakes, rivers and seas. However, what is interesting about these features is that they are made not of water, but of methane. Contrary to common belief, water is not truly required for life to exist. Rather, liquids are what is actually necessary for life. Liquid methane on Titan could potentially support hydrocarbon-based life that would be radically different from life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discovery of life on Titan could completely change the way we perceive life in the universe: life on Titan would not based on carbon, but on silicon, and exist not in water, but in liquid methane. These organisms, if found, would radically improve our knowledge of life: extraterrestrial organisms would allow scientists to study how organisms have evolved separate from Earth and how they behave in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Titan also has an atmosphere composed mainly of nitrogen, like Earth. Nitrogen is a vital part of life: it is used in many molecules such as amino acids, the building blocks of life as we know it. The atmosphere of Titan is also known to create organic molecules which then settle on the surface. With Titan’s methane rivers, these organic molecules may combine to create larger molecules and eventually life. Titan’s air pressure is quite significant; as it is 50% denser than Earth’s. A significant air pressure is required by virtually all life-forms on Earth, and would likely be required by life living on the surface of Titan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Titan is also a possible choice for human colonization, with radiation protection from Saturn’s magnetosphere. There are many hydrocarbons on Titan, which could be used as energy. The water ice on Titan could be melted for drinking and also be used to create oxygen for breathing. Sending a robot to Titan would be helpful if humanity ever decided to colonize Titan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Titan likely harbors a subsurface saline ocean, much like those of Europa and Enceladus. A lander on Titan could study twice as much as a lander on the two aforementioned moons: the Titan lander could potentially be made to investigate both the polar hydrocarbon lakes as well as the global subsurface ocean of water. This will put it into a unique position of being able to look for both carbon-based life in the ocean and silicon-based life in the hydrocarbon lakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should we visit Titan again, we will gain much knowledge about our solar system and about the universe. If we venture to Titan, we can learn how water ice, which Titan is composed mainly of, behaves at 150K temperatures. We might also find out why Titan’s surface appears so young - what is the mechanism that is renewing its surface? A spacecraft sent to Titan could potentially answer these questions, including the most important one: “Is humanity alone?”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Of all the celestial objects in the solar system, there are only two known to have stable liquid on their surface. One is Earth. The other is Titan, the largest Saturnian moon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Witty, Wise and Clever</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/creative/2019/01/12/witty-wise-and-clever.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Witty, Wise and Clever" /><published>2019-01-12T07:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T07:20:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/creative/2019/01/12/witty-wise-and-clever</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/creative/2019/01/12/witty-wise-and-clever.html">&lt;p&gt;The sun scattered rays of burning light into the airport as Witty, Wise and Clever watched the plane take off from LaGuardia, carrying their parents to “somewhere away from this noisy and New York City”. Saying that “Wise is old enough to look over you” (even though he was only five minutes older than the rest), they had left them to care for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What should we do this summer?” asked Clever.
“You’re the clever one. You’ll think of something,” responded Witty, tired from jumping up and down in anticipation of the last bell.
“Fine,” Clever said, turning to Wise. “You’re the wise one. What should we do this summer?”
“Nothing. Then nothing bad will happen to us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They agreed that it was a good plan. 
And it was, until the fluttering of a bird’s wings was heard inside the City Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you about this bird. It was a pigeon, to be exact, a perfectly normal pigeon, albeit a hungry one. It had an ordinary beak, ordinary feathers, ordinary eyes. But this pigeon happened to fly in through an open door into the city hall of New York City. The pigeon soon realized that it was trapped, and it flew around frantically, trying to find a way out. It wound in and out of hallways and narrow corridors, until a little blue tablet caught its eye. To the pigeon, it looked like food. And the pigeon hadn’t eaten in days. So the pigeon swallowed it, along with the ancient spirit, that when removed from its rightful place, would cause destruction to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the pigeon knew none of this. Having found an open window, the bird hopped into the air, oblivious to the impending doom that it was responsible for.
… 
Witty, Wise and Clever were interrupted in the middle of one of their do-nothing sessions, (which, Wise pointed out, was actually doing something), by a loud bang. 
The grass was turning into a sheet made of the word grass and all of the houses and skyscrapers turned into rooftops and floors and walls and windows, with everything inside crumbling too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can we do?” cried Clever.
“Positively nothing!” responded Wise.
“There has to be something!”
“That something is nothing!”
“Hey, stop that argument! There’s an elephant in the room - New York is falling apart!”
“We’re going to need to work together if we’re ever going to get anything done,” continued Witty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arguing ceased. Not really because of the speech by Witty, but because of the words from the ground that were slowly trickling upwards to create a majestic elephant looming over them, the letters e, l, p, h, a and t smoothing into a solid gray surface as the elephant stood up, waving its trunk in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What … just … happened?”
“I said that there was an elephant in the room.”
“And?”
“An elephant appeared!”
“So?”
“So a rock hit Wise’s head,” said Witty sincerely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moments later, a rock came tumbling down out of the sky. Wise looked up just in time to see it hit his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“NOW do you get it?”
“Yeah. But don’t ever do that again!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost in the realization of what was happening, the trio didn’t realize that the elephant was still there until it nearly trampled them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ahhh!” they cried in unison, taking off as fast as there legs would carry them, not stopping to breathe nor looking where they were running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Sassy and Nerdy, also trying to find their way out of the apparent mess that was New York City, stood on a pile of word-rubble, Nerdy casually flipping through an extremely thick handbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On page 5,095 it says that ‘All persons are to be happy at all times, even in times of disaster (car crash, tornado, alien invasion etc.)’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, I’m TOTALLY happy right now.”
“On page 5,096 it says that ‘Bikes can be found in many locations on the streets and that if one is found, it is reasonable to assume that the owner left it there for charity and it is okay to take it.’”
“There aren’t any bikes left to steal.”
“On page 5,097 it says that ‘Should a certain blue tablet ever be removed from the city hall …’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when Witty, Wise and Clever, still running from the elephant, collided with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry!” cried Clever, continuing to run. 
“Hey! Get back here! What do you think you’re doing?”
“Escaping the elephant!”
“What elephant?”
“This one!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sassy’s sassiness quickly gave way to fear as they all started to run - except for Nerdy, weighed down by his multi-thousand page book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Drop it!” Nerdy escaped just in time to see the handbook get trampled by the elephant.
“Oh, well.”
“But your handbook’s ruined!”
“Oh, well that’s okay. I have it all memorized. Like that part about the tablet-”
“Whatcha talkin’ ‘bout?”
“That tablet that’s supposed to destroy the city!”
“What?! How come you didn’t tell me ‘bout that?”
“I was going to, but then those…”
“But but but. Always your excuse.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anyway,” continued Sassy, “If only you had told me about that EARLIER, we could’ve found that stupid bird! It flew out the window in my office at that City Hall with the tablet in its beak!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why didn’t you tell us EARLIER?”
“It didn’t seem that important…” started Sassy.
“There’s no time to argue! There’s an ele- oh man. Good thing I caught myself. Well, there’s no time to lose! We have to catch this bird!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How? That’s TOTALLY as easy as falling off a log,” said Sassy, falling off a log.
“Watch your language. That sort of thing has been happening lately. Putting that aside, there’s five of us, five boroughs in the city. Each of us can take one section. We’ll meet at that Alice in Wonderland thing at Central Park, or at least where it used to be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s going to take forever to search such a large area!” Witty cried, but Clever was already running.
“Oh, well what choice do we have?” responded Nerdy. 
So they took off in separate directions.
By the end of the day, they had found many pigeons but not one with a blue tablet.
“Well, at least we pigeons to eat,” said Nerdy, examining what they had caught. “Think on the bright side! On page 2,704 of the handbook it said that ‘All persons are permitted to enjoy themselves even when they are in the worst situation possible.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, think about the negative side! What if the elephant comes back?”
There was a trampling noise. “I told you to watch your language, Sassy! The elephant’s back!”
Witty turned. If we used an idiom to make the elephant appear, we can use an idiom to make the elephant disappear, he thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When the cat’s away the mice will play.”
“What’s that supposed to mean?”
“Watch.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remains of Alice in Wonderland formed a group of playful mice, playing around with a ball of string left by the cat. The elephant’s eyes darted nervously from side to side for a few moments before it ran away, trunk waving as it trampled what was left of the trees.
“So it worked.”
“Hmm,” thought Witty, turning suddenly. “Look! I found the bird with the tablet!”
They all looked toward him - and indeed, in his palm was the bird with the tablet in its stomach, still oblivious to what it had done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How did you do that?”
“Remember the elephant? And the log? And the mice?”
“But how are we going to get this to the city hall? We’re standing on an ocean of words!”
“My iPhone still works,” suggested Sassy. “And it still has a Wifi connection!”
“We could use that to find our way to it, but the ocean is twelve feet deep! And all three of us can’t swim!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My turn,” said Wise. Thrusting out his hand as if it were a wand, he muttered, “Remember, we’re all in the same boat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All five were thrown into a small wooden boat, Clever landing on top of Wise. 
“Oww! Why did you have to throw me headfirst?” complained Clever. 
“No time for complaints! Let’s go!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frantically rowing, Witty, Wise, Clever, Sassy and Nerdy reached the building just in time. Witty dropped the tablet from his hand and let it sink… 
And the world faded to black.
… 
“I guess we did do something this summer, didn’t we?”
“Well, I think I’ve learned something. We should really enjoy the world while it lasts and not in some explosion of words.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The bird’s gone, the tablet’s back in the City Hall, that’s not going to happen again. It is going to be a nice summer after all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it was, until far off in the distance, the fluttering of wings disturbed a slight breeze blowing into an open door in the City Hall.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The sun scattered rays of burning light into the airport as Witty, Wise and Clever watched the plane take off from LaGuardia, carrying their parents to “somewhere away from this noisy and New York City”. Saying that “Wise is old enough to look over you” (even though he was only five minutes older than the rest), they had left them to care for themselves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Newton Willis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/creative/2018/10/12/newton-willis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newton Willis" /><published>2018-10-12T08:20:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T08:20:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/creative/2018/10/12/newton-willis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/creative/2018/10/12/newton-willis.html">&lt;p&gt;Stout-looking and chin held high, Jack sauntered through the sixth-grade hallway, looking like a whale in a bathtub. His beady black eyes scanned the crowd for someone new to beat up. His eyes landed on a small, confused-looking boy with wide-rimmed glasses and too-big khaki pants. The boy’s skin was ghostly white, having been bleached from hours in front of a computer screen. His blue-jay t-shirt was worn and there were loose threads hanging at the sleeves - he had obviously cut them off because they were too long. A tattered, jet-black violin case and an A+ test were stuffed into his locker. Posters of Alan Turing, Ada Lovelace and Barnaby Jack were slightly visible behind them. The words “Newton Willis” were scribbled on his beat-up folder, and a large stack of textbooks lay at his feet, all of them shiny and new with not one speck of dust. 
“Well, well. A nerd with no sense of fashion.” Jack’s slurred speech echoed through the corridors. “So, nerd, whatta ya doin’?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy’s wide eyes widened even further. His hands started fidgeting with an object, that upon closer inspection was identifiable as a breadboard with dozens of electrical components jammed onto it, turning the board into a mismatched rainbow of bright-red, dirt-brown and fuschia wires. Sprinkled in between were specks of silvery transistors and diodes. His fingers moved rapidly over it, repositioning wires while his fearful eyes swept up and down. The other kids noticed the commotion and started gathering around, talking in whispers and chanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several tense moments Newton gathered his nerve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, I’m pondering which of the 1,746 glitches I have found in the school’s grading service I should exploit to send a DDoS attack on the system and shut down the security features. Then, I will use a backdoor and gain access to the mainframe. From there, it will be a simple matter to launch my computer worm that will use a series of hacking techniques to obtain the master password in order to change my History grade from an A-minus to an A.”
Jack simply scowled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A burly kid leaned over to Jack and said, “You better not mess with him. He’s a bit paranoid. I know that from personal experience.” 
“As if I care.”
“Go ahead and see for yourself if you don’t believe me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Jack did go ahead. He pushed off with his left foot and rose into the air as his right hand curled into a fist and accelerated in an unmistakable haymaker. Two knuckles caught Newton on the shoulder, driving him into the ground, sending several folders and his circuit board flying. However, Jack’s arrogance caused him to use more force than he needed. He tried in vain to twist himself around in the air, and his menacing grin disappeared as a frightened scream took its place. There was a sickening snap as his nose hit the cold linoleum floor and a slowly growing pool of reddish liquid appeared around it. 
As if that wasn’t enough, Newton’s leg also struck the pile of textbooks, which swayed precariously before toppling and showering Jack with &lt;em&gt;Huckleberry Finn, Adventures in Calculus, Algebra 2, three Science Explorers, A Comprehensive Guide to Coding in C++&lt;/em&gt; as well as &lt;em&gt;A Study on Medieval Literature&lt;/em&gt;. The breadboard Newton was fidgeting with also just happened to land on Jack, causing two exposed wires to hit each other, short-circuiting the assembly. Electricity from three 9-volt batteries flowed through the circuit, charging twelve capacitors in rapid succession. The capacitors then discharged simultaneously, making the entire breadboard explode in a burst of sparks and setting a small fire to Jack’s crimson-red hoodie.
“Excuse me, but could you please look where you’re running? Also, you’re not supposed to be running in the halls at all. It’s against school regulations,” said Newton, who had pulled himself up from the floor and was now talking as if he was inviting him to a formal dinner instead of teaching him a lesson that Jack should have been taught years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mghdeptjs deghets mmelpedfth,” Jack grumbled from the floor. “hekjplid tghaded kkepl! Yuofh arrhre zeh zwosta fgmen zuanne!”
“Please do not attempt to insult me. You are in to condition to be so mean. Now, you need medical assistance,” Newton said with an air of contempt, his mouth curling into a maniacal smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one bothered Newton Willis after that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Stout-looking and chin held high, Jack sauntered through the sixth-grade hallway, looking like a whale in a bathtub. His beady black eyes scanned the crowd for someone new to beat up. His eyes landed on a small, confused-looking boy with wide-rimmed glasses and too-big khaki pants. The boy’s skin was ghostly white, having been bleached from hours in front of a computer screen. His blue-jay t-shirt was worn and there were loose threads hanging at the sleeves - he had obviously cut them off because they were too long. A tattered, jet-black violin case and an A+ test were stuffed into his locker. Posters of Alan Turing, Ada Lovelace and Barnaby Jack were slightly visible behind them. The words “Newton Willis” were scribbled on his beat-up folder, and a large stack of textbooks lay at his feet, all of them shiny and new with not one speck of dust. “Well, well. A nerd with no sense of fashion.” Jack’s slurred speech echoed through the corridors. “So, nerd, whatta ya doin’?”</summary></entry></feed>